# Hankook Lee

KAIST N1-917, 291 Daehak-ro, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon 34141, South Korea

■ hankook.lee@kaist.ac.kr | 🔏 hankook.github.io | 🖸 hankook | 🎓 Hankook Lee

#### Research Interests

My research goal is to develop efficient and scalable deep learning algorithms that require few or no human annotation, and ultimately apply them to real-world applications with massive data. More specifically, my research interests lie in neural architectures, data augmentations, transfer/fewshot learning, un/self-supervised learning, and so on, in various domains, for example, vision, chemistry, and tabular data.

#### **Education**

## KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)

Daejeon, South Korea

Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering

Sep. 2018 - Present

Advisor: linwoo Shin

· Advisor: Jinwoo Shin

#### KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)

Daejeon, South Korea

M.Sc. in Electrical Engineering

Mar. 2016 - Aug. 2018

KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)

Daejeon, South Korea

B.Sc. in Mathematics and Computer Science (Double major)

Mar. 2010 - Feb. 2016

• GPA: 3.93/4.3 (Magna Cum Laude)

## **Publications**

C: Conference, W: Workshop, P: Preprint, \*: Equal contribution

#### [W1] Improving Transferability of Representations via Augmentation-Aware **Self-Supervision**

Online

Hankook Lee, Kibok Lee, Kimin Lee, Honglak Lee, Jinwoo Shin

Jul 2021

· International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2021 Workshop: Self-Supervised Learning for Reasoning and Perception

#### [C6] Self-Improved Retrosynthetic Planning

Online

Junsu Kim, Sungsoo Ahn, Hankook Lee, Jinwoo Shin

International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2021

#### [C5/W] RetCL: A Selection-based Approach for Retrosynthesis via Contrastive Learning

Online

Hankook Lee, Sungsoo Ahn, Seung-Woo Seo, You Young Song, Eunho Yang, Sung Ju Hwang, Jinwoo Shin

Aug. 2021

• International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2021

NeurIPS Workshop for Machine Learning for Molecules, 2020

#### [C4] GTA: Graph Truncated Attention for Retrosynthesis

Online

Seung-Woo Seo, You Young Song, June Yong Yang, Seohui Bae, Hankook Lee, Jinwoo Shin, Sung Ju Hwang, Eunho

Feb. 2021

AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2021

#### [C3] Guiding Deep Molecular Optimization with Genetic Exploration

Online

Sungsoo Ahn, Junsu Kim, Hankook Lee, Jinwoo Shin

Dec. 2020

• Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020

#### [C2] Self-supervised Label Augmentation via Input Transformations

Online

Hankook Lee, Sung Ju Hwang, Jinwoo Shin

Jul 2020

International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2020

Received Qualcomm-KAIST Innovation Awards (2019)

Long Beach, CA, USA

[C1] Learning What and Where to Transfer Yunhun Jang\*, Hankook Lee\*, Sung Ju Hwang, Jinwoo Shin

Jul. 2019

#### • International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2019

[P] Anytime Neural Prediction via Slicing Networks Vertically Hankook Lee, Jinwoo Shin

Jul 2018

· arXiv preprint

## Work Experience

## **SAIT (Samsung Advanced Institute of Technology)**

Visiting student

• Developed ML-based retrosynthesis algorithms (AAAI 2021, IJCAI 2021 papers).

Suwon, South Korea Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2020

Juli. 2020 - Mul. 2020

Aug. 2013 - Dec. 2014

## **Frograms** Seoul, South Korea

Research and Development Engineer

- Built an automatic movie tagging system using movies' news/reviews based on Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA).
- Built a Scala-based movie rating prediction system based on non-negative matrix factorization.
- The incorporation name was changed to Watcha Inc. at 2018.

## Honors & Awards \_\_\_\_\_

2019	<b>Winner</b> , Qualcomm-KAIST Innovation Awards (ICML 2020 paper)	Daejeon, South Korea
2019	Travel award, International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2019	Long Beach, CA, USA
2013	Finalist, International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC) World Finals	St. Petersburg, Russia
2012	1st Place (Grand Prize), International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC) Asia Daejeon Regional	Daejeon, South Korea
2010	2nd Place (Gold Prize), International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC) Asia Daejeon Regional	Daejeon, South Korea
2009	<b>Gold Prize,</b> Problem Solving Division, Korea Olympiad in Informatics (KOI)	Seoul, South Korea

## Services\_\_\_\_\_

2022 Conference Reviewer, ICLR 2022

2021 **Conference Reviewer**, ICLR 2021, ICML 2021, NeurIPS 2021

2020 **Conference Reviewer,** ICLR 2020, NeruIPS 2020

2020 **Journal Reviewer**, ACM ToMPECS 2020

2018 **Journal Reviewer**, ACM ToMPECS 2018

## Invited Talks\_\_\_\_\_

2021	<b>Self-supervised Label Augmentation via Input Transformations</b> , Samsung Electronics DIT Center	Hwaseong, South Korea
2020	Learning What and Where to Transfer, Samsung Electronics DIT Center	Hwaseong, South Korea
2019	Learning What and Where to Transfer, Summer Annual Conference of IEIE	Jeju, South Korea
2018	Anytime Neural Prediction via Slicing Networks Vertically, NAVER Labs	Seongnam, South Korea

## Teaching Experience \_\_\_\_\_

2020	IA: "Semantic Segmentation and Object Detection", Samsung DS Al Expert Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	Yongin, South Korea
2019	<b>TA: "Optimization and Regulaization"</b> , SK Hynix ML Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	Daejeon, South Korea
2019	<b>TA: "Transfer and Multi-task Learning"</b> , Samsung DS AI Expert Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	Daejeon, South Korea
2018	<b>TA</b> , Seongnam-KAIST AI Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	Seongnam, South Korea
2018	TA, KB-KAIST AI Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	Daejeon, South Korea
2017	TA, KB-KAIST AI Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	Seoul, South Korea